Guide to the John Quincy Bradish Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
John Quincy Bradish papers
1775-1907
MS 1120
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1
The papers consist of John Quincy Bradish's family correspondence and papers, student papers and other writings, Yale and other memorabilia, photographs and printed matter. Much of the collection consists of records, correspondence, charts and research notes concerning Bradish family genealogy.
Bradish, John Quincy, 1832-1922
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The papers were received in 1953.
Biographical / Historical
John Quincy Bradish was born in Floyd, N.Y., March 29, 1832, the son of Clark and Hannah (Hayes) Bradish. He was the grandson of Dr. James Bradish, who served as a surgeon in the Continental Army, and a descendant of Robert Bradish, who came from England to Cambridge, Mass., in 1635.
He was given second dispute appointments in both Junior and Senior years at Yale. He belonged to Brothers in Unity.
From 1857 until 1861 Mr. Bradish was principal of the Meriden (Conn.) Institute, after which he held a similar position at the Riverside Institute at Warehouse Point, Conn., for two years. In April, 1863, he became a member of the faculty at the Collegiate and Polytechnic Institute in Brooklyn, N.Y., continuing there until 1866, when he was obliged to resign on account of trouble with his eyes. From that time until 1896 he was engaged in business in New York City as a dealer in stationery and fancy goods. Returning to New Haven, he took up the study of law in the office of Lynde Harrison (LL.B. 1860), and in January, 1900, was admitted to the bar. He afterwards practiced in New Haven for a while, giving especial attention to the writing of wills and the securing of patents. He was later engaged in the real estate business in Providence and at Fort Stockton, Texas. Since 1916 he had conducted a stationery business in Anthony, R.I. He was a member of the First Church of Christ Scientist in Providence. In 1920 Mr. Bradish established a fund of over $3,800 at Yale which will eventually be available for scholarship loans.
He was married December 3, 1858, to S. Jennie Mather, whose death occurred November 1, 1859. On August 28, 1862, he was married a second time to Susannah Rikeman, daughter of Joseph Pearce and Cornelia (Peterson) Simpson. She died August 3, 1904. By his second marriage Mr. Bradish had a son, Stanley Pearce, who graduated from the Yale School of Law in 1899, and a daughter, Cornelia Belle, who died in infancy. Surviving him are his son; a grandson, Donald Millard Bradish, of Anthony, R.I.; and a sister, Mrs. Emily White, of Oak Park, Ill.
Taken from Yale University Obituary Record, 1922-1923.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of John Quincy Bradish's family correspondence and papers, student papers and other writings, Yale and other memorabilia, photographs and printed matter. Much of the collection consists of records, correspondence, charts and research notes concerning Bradish family genealogy.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Photographs; Businessmen; Educators; Lawyers; Bradish, John Quincy, 1832-1922; Bradish family; Yale College (1718-1887). Class of 1857; Yale University -- Students
- Inventory
  - Bradish family correspondence and papers
    - Dr. James Bradish (1752-1815), [1775?], 1791-1803 (Box 1)
    - Clark (1788-1882) and John [sons of James Bradish], 1821-1841 (Box 1)
  - John Quincy Bradish
    - "Miscellaneous papers written at Whitestown, & c.", [1850?] (Box 1)
    - Compositions and disputes at Yale College, 1854-1856 (Box 1)
    - Incoming letters, mainly relating to genealogy, 1877-1903 (Box 1)
  - Bradish genealogical records
    - Pages 1-402, undated (Box 1)
    - Pages 403-1168 and unpaginated, undated (Box 2)
  - Genealogical charts of various family branches, undated (Box 2)
  - Genealogical research notes, undated (Box 2)
  - Photographs of Clark Bradish, John Q. Bradish, Susanna Rikeman (Simpson) Bradish, Stanley P. Bradish, the family cottage in Cottage City, Massachusetts, and several unidentified persons, undated (Box 2)
  - Yale and other memorabilia, clippings, and miscellaneous printed matter, including printed forms, 1856-1907 (Box 2)